It's not uncommon to see students skipping class on the rooftop in manga and such,
En los mangas,
but if you actually took a nap up there, you'd get a sunburn like no other.
pero si te echaras un rato allí, acabarías quemándote por el sol.
I think third period is about to start for everyone else.
Creo que está a punto de empezar la tercera hora.
I pretty much always skipped classes,
Yo siempre hacía pellas
and Adachi rarely ever came to school.
y Adachi apenas veía a clase.
We happened to meet up here by chance,
Nos conocimos por casualidad
and ended up spending a lot of time together.
y acabamos pasando un montón de tiempo juntas.
Do you mind if I serve next?
¿Te importa si saco ahora?
Sure?
¿Estás segura?
I found out how to do that serve online.
Aprendí a hacer ese servicio por internet.
But I didn't have a racket at home, so I practiced with a rice paddle.
Como no tengo paleta en casa, practiqué con una de cocina.
No fair using curveballs on amateurs like me.
No es justo usar una bola curva contra una principiante.
You lack ambition, young Shimamura.
Te falta ambición, pequeña Shimamura.
And that's not my... fault!
Y no es culpa mía.
When we're skipping class like this,
Cuando nos saltamos las clases,
we can usually sense if the other is here.
normalmente sabemos si la otra está aquí.
So you're getting worse...
Normalmente nos encontramos aquí.
Let's do this!
Vamos allá.
I guess third period was PE class.
Así que tocaba Educación Física a tercera.
What if they come up here?
¿Y si hubieran subido?
Why don't we open the windows and jump?
¿Abrimos la ventana y saltamos?
What?! But we're on the second floor!
¿Qué? ¡Estamos en el segundo piso!
Wouldn't we break our legs?
¿No nos romperíamos las piernas?
Ah, I see that you lack calcium in your diet.
Ya veo que a tu dieta le falta calcio.
I really don't like that interpretation.
No me gusta esa forma de verlo.
Crap. This is sorta exciting.
Mierda, esto es emocionante.
I don't think they realize we're up here, though.
No creo que se den cuenta de que estamos aquí.
Maybe I'll just drink some milk with my lunch today.
Creo que hoy beberé leche con el almuerzo.
So my legs don't break if we ever have to jump.
Así no me romperé las piernas cuando salte.
I see. So you've decided to strengthen your bones.
Ya veo. Has decidido fortalecer tus huesos.
This time we spent together where nothing else mattered
Los ratos que pasamos juntas en los que no importaba nada más
always felt so nice.
eran muy agradables.
Ugh, I can't anymore.
No puedo más.
It's so hot!
Qué calor.
Wanna go outside?
¿Quieres salir fuera?
It's almost lunchtime anyway.
Ya casi es la hora de comer.
My, how lewd. Our school's...
Vaya, qué indecente. La…
Um...
Esto…
Dignity?
¿Dignidad?
Yeah, that! Our school's dignity is at stake here.
Eso es. Te estás jugando la dignidad del insti.
It's lunchtime, but what should I do?
Ya es la hora de comer. ¿Qué hago?
Yeah, yeah. We can't have you go out in that state.
Sí, no podemos sacarte en estas condiciones.
I'll just go.
Déjalo, ya voy yo.
I'll go next time.
Yo iré para la próxima.
You and I always seem to have different opinions about "next time."
Tenemos conceptos muy distintos de "la próxima vez".
Oh, you probably want your usual danish,
Ya sé que quieres el pan de siempre,
but do you want milk today?
pero ¿con leche?
Water, please.
Con agua.
Roger.
A la orden.
Doing bad things with Adachi is pretty fun.
Me divierte hacer cosas malas con Adachi.
Is it because I got hooked doing this with Adachi,
¿Será porque me he acostumbrado a hacerlas con ella
or do I just get a rush doing bad things?
o porque me gusta hacer ese tipo de travesuras?
The answer's obvious, but...
La respuesta es obvia,
I'll leave things ambiguous for now.
pero dejaré las ambigüedades de momento.
What is she even doing?
¿Qué estará haciendo?
Shimamura was the first one to be up here on the second floor of the gymnasium.
Ella fue la primera en llegar a la segunda planta del gimnasio.
She still looked like a middle schooler,
Parecía como si estuviera en secundaria,
so I figured she was a first-year like me.
así que supuse que estaba en primero.
A-Adachi, was it?
¿Te llamabas Adachi?
Yeah?
Así es.
Um, we're in the same class.
Estamos en la misma clase.
My nickname's Shimamura, but in hiragana.
Soy Shimamura, escrito en hiragana.
Shimamura...
Shimamura…
Do you come here often?
¿Vienes mucho por aquí?
I just happened to stop by today. What about you?
Estoy aquí por casualidad. ¿Y tú?
Pretty much the same.
Más o menos igual.
They're so loud.
Hacen mucho ruido.
Right?
¿A que sí?
Hiyah!
¡Vete!
Are you able to touch them?
¿Te gusta tocarlas?
Cicadas aren't too bad.
A las cigarras, sí.
Think it'll stay on?
¿Se quedará quieta?
How many days do you think it has left?
¿Cuántos días crees que le quedan?
I dunno.
Ni idea.
Yeah...
Cierto.
How much longer do you want it to live?
¿Cuánto tiempo más crees que vivirá?
Fifteen days... I think.
Creo que… unos 15 días.
Fifteen days later,
Quince días después,
Shimamura's hands were covered in dirt when she came up to the second floor.
Shimamura tenía las manos llenas de barro cuando llegó al gimnasio.
That was my first encounter with Shimamura.
Aquel fue mi primer encuentro con Shimamura.
Adachi!
Adachi.
I got you the last danish.
Te he traído el último pan.
Here's your water.
Toma el agua.
Thanks.
Gracias.
This was still when
Aquello pasó
I didn't consider Shimamura my friend yet.
cuando todavía no me consideraba su amiga.
"Tea"
Té
"Learning Table Tennis From Zero"
Tenis de mesa para principiantes
I guess they have a book for everything. Dang, that's expensive.
Hoy en día hay libros para todo, pero qué caro.
Hey, it's Shimamura.
Anda, Shimamura.
Hino.
Hino.
Whatcha lookin' at?
¿Qué miras?
Smash! You joining the table tennis club, Shimamura?
-¿Vas a ir al club de tenis de mesa? -Hino es una compañera muy normal.
She's never even dyed her hair before.
Nunca se ha teñido el pelo.
She's never even shoplifted, either.
Tampoco ha robado nunca.
"Learning Table Tennis From Zero"
Tenis de mesa para principiantes
She's apparently never pulled the hair of a girl from another school, either.
Tampoco le ha tirado del pelo a otra chica.
Hey!
¡Hola!
My other classmate, Nagafuji, is your usual bespectacled girl with big boobs.
Nagafuji, mi otra compañera, es la típica con gafas y tetas grandes.
Need I say more?
¿Hace falta que diga más?
Her big boobs and her big attitude make her pretty mature...
Sus pedazo de tetas y su actitud son bastante maduras.
...but she's a bit dumb.
Sin embargo, es bastante tonta.
Hino, do you have an excuse for that blatant sexual harassment?
Hino, ¿qué excusa tienes para ese descarado acoso sexual?
Nagafuji is too self-conscious,
Como Nagafuji es tan cohibida,
so I thought I'd lighten the mood.
lo hice para levantar los ánimos.
Really?
¿Ah, sí?
Well, when they're this big, the boys always look.
Es que unas tetas tan grandes dejan embobados a los tíos.
Of course, I'm self-conscious.
Claro que soy tímida.
I'm sure all the boys in class staring at your boobies
Fijo que los tíos de clase que te las han mirado
have fondled them at least ten times in their minds.
han soñado mil veces con tocártelas.
What?! That's gross.
¿Qué? Pues qué asco.
That's the price you pay for being famous.
Ese es el precio de la fama.
Oh, whoops. My hand slipped.
Anda, se me ha resbalado la mano.
Apparently, Hino and Nagafuji have been friends since they were little.
Hino y Nagafuji son amigas desde que eran pequeñas.
I became friends with them after we got into high school,
Yo me hice amiga de ellas cuando entramos en el insti,
so my distance with them varies.
así que no tengo tanta confianza con ellas.
But when it comes to distance,
Pero en cuanto a eso,
being as close as you can be isn't always the best option.
ser íntimas no es siempre la mejor opción.
If you get too close, you might fight and have misunderstandings.
Ser tan amigas puede dar lugar a peleas y malentendidos.
Oh, yeah. The other day at the fishing hole there was someone in a spacesuit...
El otro día vi a alguien vestido con un traje espacial en la zona de pesca…
Hey, look over there!
¡Anda, mirad!
I think relationships with others
Creo que las relaciones
are like free diving.
son como bucear.
Hey, who was that? Wasn't she in our class in like April?
¿Quién era? ¿No lleva en nuestra clase desde abril?
You say that like every time we see her.
Siempre dices lo mismo cuando la ves.
"Green Tea"
Té verde
Her name is Adachi.
Se llama Adachi.
She's our classmate.
Está en nuestra clase.
She's definitely a certified delinquent. Teacher-approved.
Pues, según los profes, es toda una delincuente.
Is she one of yours, Shimamura?
¿Es amiga tuya?
Who knows?
Quién sabe.
You keep sinking deeper and deeper,
Te hundes cada vez más
and things start disappearing around you.
y lo que te rodea empieza a desaparecer.
You struggle to breathe, so you try to get back to the water's surface.
Cuando te cuesta respirar, intentas volver a la superficie.
And then you poke your head out for a breath of air
Entonces, sacas la cabeza para respirar
before sinking deeper yet again.
antes de volver a sumergirte.
If you keep repeating that cycle...
Si repites ese ciclo…
Morning.
Buenas.
Adachi...
Adachi…
Hey, you're late today.
Hola. Hoy llegas tarde.
Oh, I...
No, es que…
...thought I'd just head home,
había pensado en irme a casa,
but I heard the sound of a ping-pong ball.
pero escuché el sonido de una pelota.
I saw you yesterday.
Ayer te vi.
Yeah, you did.
Sí, ya lo sé.
Where's your school bag?
¿Dónde está tu mochila?
In my bicycle's basket.
En la cesta de mi bici.
I see.
Ya veo.
Well, I'm heading home.
Bueno, me voy.
Okay...
Vale…
Say, Adachi.
Oye, Adachi.
"Let's go to class today," or "Let's walk home together today."
Entre "vamos a clase" o "volvamos juntas a casa",
Which would you prefer?
¿cuál prefieres?
In that case... I'll just go kill some time somewhere until school's over... I guess.
En ese caso,
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Perdona.
You didn't have to be sitting the same exact way.
No tenías que sentarte como el otro día.
Sorry, it started raining.
Perdona, es que está lloviendo.
Well, the rain's not your fault.
Bueno, no es culpa tuya.
Which way is your house, Shimamura?
¿Por dónde está tu casa?
This way.
Por ahí.
Oh, I thought so.
Me lo temía.
Here, hold this.
Toma.
I just figured your house was pretty far from mine.
Me suponía que tu casa quedaba lejos de la mía.
I live this way.
Yo vivo por ahí.
So, whose home should we go home to first?
¿Por qué casa quieres pasar primero?
That's a novel way of putting it.
Qué forma tan original de decirlo.
Then... Why don't we go to your place first?
¿Te parece que vayamos primero a la tuya?
Okay.
De acuerdo.
Riding a bike like this is a crime, you know?
Sabes que montar así en bici es un delito, ¿verdad?
Like that matters. We're delinquents.
Da igual, somos delincuentes.
Good point.
Tienes razón.
Man, being delinquents rules.
Pues mola ser delincuentes.
It sure does.
Por supuesto.
So I guess you actually have friends.
Así que tienes amigas.
Oh, you mean Hino and Nagafuji?
¿Te refieres a Hino y Nagafuji?
I thought you were always up there because you didn't have friends.
Creía que ibas arriba porque no tenías amigos.
What about you, Adachi?
¿Y tú, Adachi?
Do you have friends?
¿Tienes amigos?
You're probably my only one.
Creo que tú eres la única.
That's so sad!
¡Pues qué triste!
Killing time outside of school and then going home together is weird.
Es raro pasar tiempo fuera del insti y luego irnos juntas a casa.
This is definitely weird,
Es muy raro,
but the idea sounded amusing and elating.
pero la idea sonaba interesante y alegre.
If either of us were actually honor students, we'd say,
Si fuéramos alumnas ejemplares, diríamos:
"We shouldn't be doing this!"
"No deberíamos hacerlo" o algo así.
And try to steer the other back down the right path with the power of friendship,
Además usaríamos la amistad para llevar a la otra por el buen camino.
but we were both pretty irresponsible.
Sin embargo, las dos éramos unas irresponsables.
So we were just dragging each other down deeper.
Solo nos estábamos hundiendo más.
"School" "Shrine" "House with the red roof" "Storehouse"
Casa con el tejado rojo
So I go through here, and then... to get back to my house...
Tiro por aquí y luego… para volver a casa…
That's a pretty decent walk.
Pues es un buen trecho.
Shimamura!
¡Shimamura!
Here, I got you a towel.
Toma una toalla.
Huh? Wh-Whoa.
¿Qué? Vaya.
Thanks.
Gracias.
Sorry.
Perdón.
Huh? About what?
¿Por?
I feel bad for making you take a really long way home.
Me siento mal por hacerte volver por el camino largo.
Want me to give you a ride home?
¿Quieres que te lleve?
Huh? No. This whole ride would be pointless, then.
No. Entonces, este viaje no habría tenido sentido.
I guess you have a point.
Tienes razón.
Okay, I'm going home.
Bueno, me voy.
Yeah, I'll probably see you tomorrow.
Sí, hasta mañana seguramente.
When I looked down at Adachi's head from the back of her bicycle,
Cuando miraba la cabeza de Adachi desde la bici,
I noticed her hair that usually looked so pretty with her face
me fijé en lo bien que le quedaba el pelo con la cara.
also looked like some floofy creature.
Aunque parecía una criatura blandita.
Maybe I looked the same way.
Quizás yo sea igual.
What a weird day.
Qué día tan extraño.
See? I told you there were noises coming from upstairs.
¿Lo ves? Te dije que los ruidos vienen de arriba.
Huh? I guess you really were playing table tennis.
¿Qué? Sabía que estabas jugando al tenis de mesa.
Did you really say, "Gack" to your friend?
¿Así reaccionas con tus amigas?
Shimamura...
Shimamura…
Adachi...
Adachi…
So, how'd you know I was here?
¿Cómo sabíais que estaba aquí?
You were looking at the table tennis book at the bookstore.
Por el libro que viste en la tienda.
Whoopsie.
Vaya.
So... Is that Adachi over there?
Oye, ¿esa de ahí es Adachi?
Um... I think that's pretty self-explanatory, but yeah.
Creo que está claro, sí.
Yup, Adachi.
Ya veo. Adachi.
You guys were friends?
¿Sois amigas?
Well, yeah.
Sí.
Then yesterday... Well, whatever.
Entonces, lo de ayer… Bueno, déjalo.
I'm Nagafuji.
Yo me llamo Nagafuji.
I'm Hino.
Y yo Hino.
Nagafuji and Hino... Got it.
Nagafuji y Hino… Entendido.
Nice to meet you.
Encantada.
Um... I bought us some bread.
A ver… He traído pan.
I'm surprised they never found you guys during PE class.
Me sorprende que no os hayan pillado en Educación Física.
We stayed pretty quiet whenever there was class.
Cuando tienen clase nos quedamos calladas.
Which one do you want, Adachi?
¿Cuál prefieres, Adachi?
I'll take whichever one you like, Shimamura.
El que más te guste, Shimamura.
Are you free on Sunday, Shimamura?
¿Estás libre el domingo, Shimamura?
This week? I think so.
¿Este domingo? Creo que sí.
Then wanna go to the fishing hole?
¿Quieres ir a la zona de pesca?
That kid in the spacesuit I was telling you about is a riot.
El niño del traje espacial es la monda.
Are you basically just asking me to go fishing with you?
¿Me estás pidiendo que vaya a pescar contigo?
No, no. That's just a bonus.
No, no, eso es un extra.
They said they wanted to meet you when I mentioned you.
Cuando te mencioné, dijo que quería conocerte.
Why don't you just take Nagafuji with you?
¿Por qué no te llevas a Nagafuji?
I have club.
Tengo club.
Come on, let's go!
Venga, vente.
Hm... Yeah, sure.
Bueno, vale.
Heck yes!
Toma ya.
Okay, we're going to the fishing hole on Sunday.
Pues quedamos en ir a la zona de pesca el domingo.
The next day, Adachi didn't come here.
Al día siguiente, Adachi no vino.
There was a lot I didn't know about Adachi,
Había muchas cosas que no sabía de ella
and that frustrated me at times.
y eso me frustraba a veces.
What I did know was what I felt.
Lo que sí sabía era lo que sentía.
After seeing Hino and Nagafuji having a blast up here yesterday, I realized again...
Después de ver a Hino y Nagafuji pasándoselo bien ayer, me di cuenta…
That's not what I wanted.
de que eso no era lo que quería.
Adachi might not show up again for a while.
Puede que Adachi no aparezca por un tiempo.
If I was super unlucky, I may not see her again until graduation.
Si no tengo suerte, puede que no la vea hasta la graduación.
That was totally possible.
Es posible.
I guess my luck does suck. Welp...
Qué mala suerte tengo…
Blammo!
¡Pum!
A-Adachi?
¿Adachi?
Sorry...
Perdona.
I was planning to stop but didn't make it in time.
He intentado frenar, pero no lo he conseguido a tiempo.
I'm pretty sure I heard you say, "Blammo."
Estoy casi segura que dijiste "pum"…
Wait, are you sure about this?
¿Estás segura?
About what?
¿De qué?
Well, your house isn't this way.
Tu casa no está por aquí.
Yeah, but...
Sí, pero…
Yeah, you're right.
Tienes razón.
Shimamura, here.
Toma, Shimamura.
Huh? Wait, what?
¿Eh? ¿Qué es?
"Eggy Bread"
Pan con huevo
I was going to give them to you during lunch today.
Pensaba dártelos hoy durante el almuerzo.
Lunch?
¿Almuerzo?
Oh, so this is "next time."
¿Esta es "la próxima vez"?
I'm glad you weren't going home with your other friends.
Me alegra que no te hayas ido con tus otras amigas.
I wouldn't have been able to give them to you.
De haberlo hecho, no te lo habría dado.
What?
¿Qué?
Oh, nothing.
Nada.
Adachi had said that I was her only friend.
Adachi dijo que yo era su única amiga.
I guess that's all there is to it then.
Supongo que eso era todo.
This was about all I could ask
Era todo lo que podía pedir
and this was all Adachi was able to say right now.
y era todo lo que Adachi estaba dispuesta a decir.
Adachi.
Adachi.
You are walking me all the way home, right?
Vas a llevarme a casa, ¿verdad?
Yeah, that was my intention.
Sí, esa era mi intención.
Look at me! I'm a plane! Vroom!
¡Mira, soy un avión!
The slight elation that I felt had given me wings.
La pequeña alegría que sentí me dio alas.
I wonder how many steps it'll take before embarrassment sets in.
¿Cuánto quedará para que esto dé vergüenza?
So, what's Adachi like?
¿Cómo es Adachi?
What is she like? Um, normal?
¿A qué te refieres? Normal, ¿no?
That explains nothing, my dear Shimamura.
Eso no me aclara nada, mi querida Shimamura.
I don't know how much I should tell you.
Y yo no sé cuánto puedo contar.
Adachi likes water and usually drinks mineral water.
Le gusta el agua y normalmente bebe agua mineral.
She doesn't seem to care about brands.
No le interesan las marcas.
I see. So Adachi is a Namekian.
Ya veo. Es una namekiana.
I haven't seen her regrow any limbs yet, though. Also...
Pero todavía no he visto que le hayan crecido las extremidades…
Anything biting?
¿No pica nada?
The spacesuit was so white that it just compounded their awkward presence.
El traje era tan blanco que combinaba con su extraña presencia.
Suddenly, a small astronaut stood before me.
De repente se plantó ante mí un pequeño astronauta.
"Episode 1: Playing Ping-Pong in Our Uniforms"
Episodio 1: Jugando al tenis de mesa en uniforme
"Next Time: 'Adachi Question'"
Próximo episodio: La pregunta de Adachi
Explain the difference between table tennis and ping-pong.
Diferencias con el tenis de mesa.
When you're playing seriously, it's table tennis. Ping-pong is just for fun.
El tenis de mesa es serio, no por diversión.
But what about when you play ping-pong seriously?
-¿Y el ping-pong serio? -Es tenis de mesa.
But what about table tennis for fun?
-¿Y el tenis de mesa por diversión? -¡Es ping-pong!
Ping-pong is but table tennis.
Ping-pong es tenis de mesa.
I tried to sound philosophical.
Intentaba sonar filosófica.